Jamiu Salaudeen

Front End Developer

Nigeria

+2347084195933

jamiumuhammed011@gmail.com

Solution-driven Front End developer adept at contributing to highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions and determining customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and related libraries and frameworks. Built products for desktop and mobile app users over 2+ years, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices and speed. Designed and developed web applications across multiple API's, third party integrations and databases.

Skills

- Front End framework design
- Developer collaboration
- Teamwork and collaboration
- Attention to details
- Organization and Time management

Work History

• Front End developer

Topperize (Nov, 2022 - till date)

- Developed a Virtual Top-Up app that enables individual to buy and sell airtime from either their bank or their online wallet.
- Tested web-based product functionality an delivered iterations to customer.

Jamiu Salaudeen 1

- Coded using React, TypeScript and TailwindCss, to develop features for both mobile and desktop platforms.
- Improved tools to boost user interaction and deliver design versatility.

Front End Developer

Internship at **HNG** (Oct, 2022 - Dec, 2022)

- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements.
- Use regulatory and compliance standards for user interface designs.
- Teamed on user-centric design strategy in translation of UX and business requirements into coded solutions.

• Front End Developer

Internship at **Zuri** (Jul, 2022 - Sep, 2022)

- Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers.
- Developed a mobile and web responsive user interface
- Collaborated with Designers and Product managers to achieve the project requirement.

Education

• MB;BS: Medicine and surgery

University of Ilorin - Ilorin, Kwara State.

Languages

- English [proficient]
- Arabic [Elementary]

Certifications

Jamiu Salaudeen 2

- Certified Full Stack Developer, Zuri
 [https://drive.google.com/file/d/1TlbyLSkpB5WMa3uPz2qbEqHvHIEhGSUJ/view?
 usp=share_link] (Jul, 2022 Sep, 2022)
- Certified Front End Developer, Udacity
 [https://drive.google.com/file/d/1TkP1q_MfCE55S6olvBA7qOD2QyJBnRd4/view?
 usp=share_link] (Aug, 2022 Oct, 2022)
- Certified Front End Developer, **HNG** (Oct, 2022 Dec, 2022)

Jamiu Salaudeen 3